colorofchange.org 2019-03-08

# Privacy Policy – ColorOfChange.com

Last updated: April 9, 2018

## Introduction

This website, https://www.colorofchange.org, (the “Site”) is operated by ColorOfChange.org (“We” or “Us”).

ColorOfChange.org is a California nonprofit public benefit corporation exempt from taxation under section 501(c)(4) of the Internal Revenue Code dedicated to strengthening the voice of Black Americans and pressuring targets in government and corporate America to take actions that create important real-world changes for Black folks and our allies.

ColorOfChange.org is committed to protecting your privacy online. By providing Personal Information to us, you agree to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy.

## Updates to this Privacy Policy

Please review this privacy policy periodically because we modify it from time to time. Please take a look at the “LAST UPDATED” legend at the top of this page to see when this Privacy Policy was last revised. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will become effective when we post the revised Privacy Policy on the Site. Each time you visit this Site or provide us with information through the Site, by doing so you are accepting practices described in the Privacy Policy in effect at that time.

## Your Personal Information

“Personal Information” is information that identifies you as an individual, such as:

  * Name
  * Postal address
  * Telephone number
  * Email address
  * Credit and debit card number

### How we use Personal Information

We may use Personal Information:

  * To allow you to sign petitions, complete surveys and send messages elected officials and corporate leaders through the Site.
  * To respond to your inquiries and fulfill your requests, such as to send you updates by e-mail. (For information about how to unsubscribe from certain e-mails, please see the “Choices and Access” section below.)
  * To communicate with you about ColorOfChange.org campaigns (including by telephone, if you have voluntarily provided your telephone number through the Site. For information about how to unsubscribe from campaign-related telephone contacts, please see the “Choices and Access” section below.)
  * To send you important information regarding the Site, changes to our terms, conditions, and policies and/or other administrative information.
  * To process your donation or payment.
  * To send you communications from like-minded partner organizations that we believe may be of interest to you.
  * For our business purposes, such as data analysis, enhancing our website, improving our services, identifying usage trends and determining the effectiveness of our campaigns.
  * As we believe to be necessary or appropriate: (a) under applicable law, including laws outside your country of residence; (b) to comply with legal process; (c) to respond to requests from public and government authorities including public and government authorities outside your country of residence; (d) to enforce our terms and conditions; (e) to protect our operations or those of any of our affiliates; (f) to protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, and/or that of our affiliates, you or others; and (g) to allow us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain.

### How Personal Information is disclosed

Your Personal Information may be disclosed:

  * To third parties (such as elected officials, news publications, and other targets) when you voluntarily provide such information or when you use certain services available on the Site (such as sending messages to third parties, signing petitions or completing surveys). Please note that any information and materials that you post or disclose through these services may be published on the Site and may become public information that is available to visitors to the Site and members of the general public. We urge you to be very careful when deciding to disclose your Personal Information, or any other information, on the Site.
  * To our third-party service providers who provide services such as website hosting, data analysis, donation and payment processing, order fulfillment, infrastructure provision, IT services, customer service, email delivery services, credit card processing, auditing services and other similar services to enable them to provide services.
  * To our affiliates to permit them to send you communications.
  * To a third party in the event of any reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of our business or assets (including in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings).
  * As we believe to be necessary or appropriate: (a) under applicable law, including laws outside your country of residence; (b) to comply with legal process; (c) to respond to requests from public and government authorities including public and government authorities outside your country of residence; (d) to enforce our terms and conditions; (e) to protect our operations or those of any of our affiliates; (f) to protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, and/or that of our affiliates, you or others; and (g) to allow us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain.

## Other Information

### Other Information We Collect

“Other Information” is any information that does not reveal your specific identity or does not directly relate to an individual, such as:

  * Browser information
  * Server log files
  * Information collected through cookies, pixel tags and other technologies
  * Demographic information and other information provided by you
  * Aggregated information

### How we collect Other Information

We and our third party service providers may collect Other Information in a variety of ways, including:

  * Through your browser: Certain information is collected by most browsers, such as your Media Access Control (MAC) address, computer type (Windows or Macintosh), screen resolution, operating system version and Internet browser type and version.
  * Through server log files: An Internet Protocol (IP) address is a number that is automatically assigned to the computer that you are using by your Internet Service Provider (ISP), and is identified and logged automatically in our server log files whenever a user visits the Site, along with the time of the visit and the page(s) that were visited. We use IP addresses for purposes such as calculating Site usage levels, helping diagnose server problems, and administering the Site.
  * Using cookies: Cookies allow a web server to transfer data to a computer for record keeping and other purposes. We and our service providers use cookies and other technologies to, among other things, better serve you with more tailored information and facilitate your ongoing access to and use of the Site, as well as for online tracking purposes. If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, there is a simple procedure in most browsers that allows you to decline the use of cookies. To learn more about cookies, please visit <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/>. If you choose to decline cookies, some or all of the features and functionality of the Site may not be available to you.
  * Using embedded images, pixel tags and other similar technologies: We may use embedded images or pixel tags (also known as web beacons and clear GIFs) in connection with some Site pages and email messages to, among other things, track the actions of Site users and email recipients, measure the success of our marketing campaigns and compile statistics about Site usage and response rates. URLs contained in emails contain an ID that enables us to identify Site users who take an action using a page from the Site, and we may use these URLs to simplify the process of signing petitions and completing surveys. We may occasionally present a shortened URL that references a longer URL that contains an ID. We do this to simplify the display, to prevent links from becoming broken when copied, and to ensure compatibility with email programs that do not handle long URLs. When a shortened URL is displayed in an email, you will see the full URL in the browser’s address bar when you access the page.
  * From you: We may collect demographic information such as your location, as well as other information, such as your preferred means of communication, when you voluntarily provide this information to us. Unless combined with Personal Information, this information does not personally identify you or any other user of the Site.
  * By aggregating information: We may aggregate Personal Information so that the end-product does not personally identify you or any other user of the Site, for example, by using Personal Information to calculate the percentage of our users who have a particular telephone area code. Aggregated Personal Information does not personally identify you or any other user of the Site.

### How we use and disclose Other Information

Because Other Information does not personally identify you, we may use and disclose Other Information for any purpose. For example, we may analyze aggregated information from Site users and their actions for research related to improving our impact on issues affecting Black Americans. In some instances, we may combine Other Information with Personal Information (such as combining your name with your zip code). If we combine any Other Information with Personal Information, the combined information will be treated by us as Personal Information as long as it is combined.

## Security

We use reasonable organizational, technical and administrative measures to protect Personal Information under our control. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure, please immediately notify us of the issue by contacting us in accordance with the “Contacting Us” section below.

## Choices and Access

### Your Choices Regarding Our Use and Disclosure of Your Personal Information

We give you many choices regarding our use and disclosure of your Personal Information. You may opt out from:

  * Receiving campaign or marketing-related emails from us: If you no longer want to receive campaign or marketing-related emails from us on a going-forward basis, you may do so here.
  * Receiving campaign or marketing-related telephone calls from us. If you do not with so receive campaign or marketing-related telephone calls from us on a going-forward basis, you may opt out of receiving campaign related telephone calls by contacting us using this form.
  * Our sharing of your Personal Information with affiliates for their marketing purposes: If you would prefer that we do not share your Personal Information on a going-forward basis with our affiliates for their marketing purposes, you may opt out of this sharing by contacting us using this form.
  * We will try to comply with your request(s) as soon as reasonably practicable. Please note that if you opt out as described above, we will not be able to remove your Personal Information from the databases of our affiliates or unaffiliated third parties with which we have already shared your Personal Information (i.e., to which we have already provided your Personal Information as of the date that we implement your opt out request). Please also note that if you do opt out of receiving marketing-related messages from us, we may still send important administrative messages to you, and you cannot opt out from receiving administrative messages.

We will try to comply with your request(s) as soon as reasonably practicable. Please note that if you opt out as described above, we will not be able to remove your Personal Information from the databases of our affiliates or unaffiliated third parties with which we have already shared your Personal Information (i.e., to which we have already provided your Personal Information as of the date that we implement your opt out request). Please also note that if you do opt out of receiving marketing-related messages from us, we may still send important administrative messages to you, and you cannot opt out from receiving administrative messages.

### How You May Access or Change Your Personal Information

If you would like to review or update your Personal Information that has been previously provided to us, you may contact us using this form.

In your request, please make clear what information you would like to have changed. We will try to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable. We are not responsible for changing information from the databases of third parties with whom we have already shared your Personal Information

## Third-Party Sites

This Privacy Policy does not address, and we are not responsible for, the privacy, information or other practices of any third parties, including any third party operating any site to which this Site contains a link. The inclusion of a link on the Site does not imply endorsement of the linked site by us or by our affiliates.

## Donations

We use a third-party service provider (the “Payment Service”) to process your donations. If you wish to make a donation using the Site, you will be directed to a webpage that is hosted by the Payment Service (or its service providers) and not by us (the “Payment Service Page”). Any Personal Information that you provide through the Payment Service Page will be collected by the Payment Service rather than by us, and will be subject to the Payment Service’s privacy policy rather than this Privacy Policy. Please note that this policy does not address the collection and use of information through the Payment Service Page or the privacy or information practices of the Payment Service. We have no control over, and shall not be responsible for, the Payment Service’s use of information collected through the Payment Service Page.

## Use of Site by Minors

The Site is not directed to individuals under the age of thirteen, and we request that these individuals do not provide Personal Information through the Site.

## Jurisdictional Issues

The Site is controlled and operated by us from the United States and is not intended to subject us to the laws or jurisdiction of any state, country or territory other than that of the United States.

## Contacting Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us using this form.

Please note that email communications are not always secure, so please do not include sensitive information in your messages to us.
